<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<projects>

    <project>
        <universalname>SkateSidescroller</universalname>
        <name>Skate Sidescroller</name>
        <category>Unity</category>
        <languages>
            <language>C#</language>
            <language>Unity 2D</language>
        </languages>
        <descriptions>
            <description>
            This game is an example of one of my spontaneous bouts of coding.
            </description>
            <description>
            During the summer of one of my highschool years, I decided to revisit Unity and create a game inspired by one of my close friends.
            I combined his passion in skateboarding with my passion in game development, and this side scrolling skateboarding game was born.
            </description>
            <description>
            This is the first game that I have developed without much help from online resources and where I relied mostly on prior game development experience.
            I heavily used my prior knowledge in game loops and game state to achieve the final result.
            I also explored creating power ups which alter the character's traits, such as number of jumps, lives, and speed.
            All the art and animations are mostly done by yours truly (and yes I know they could use some work).
            </description>
        </descriptions>
    </project>

    <project>
        <universalname>2DRPG</universalname>
        <name>2D RPG</name>
        <category>Gamemaker Studio</category>
        <languages>
            <language>GML</language>
        </languages>
        <descriptions>
            <description>
            A game that really impressed me with its minimalistic and unconventional combat system was none other than Toby Fox's Undertale.
            This game was beautiful in its own right, and it inspired me to try making a game of my own using the same engine: Gamemaker Studio.
            </description>
            <description>
            This game was made following a tutorial series for Gamemaker Studio on YouTube.
            As I learned each part of the program, I took the idea and ran with it.
            </description>
            <description>
            Introduced how to make a simple AI so slimes follow the player?
            Create a giant crab boss that charges up for 2 seconds and then rams the player at full speed.
            </description>
            <description>
            Taught how to make enemies drop experience orbs?
            Make it so that experience orbs and health orbs explode from the enemy and return to the player.
            </description>
            <description>
            Taught how to spawn objects in the game?
            Allow the player to fire multiple fireballs which hurt and damage enemies (this wasn't actually implemented properly as my tiny brain at the
            time could not comprehend how to do it).
            </description>
            <description>
            Gamemaker Studio was my first game engine prior to Unity.
            Its built in language, GML, was very easy to learn and solidified many programming basics that I have learned during highschool.
            GML introduced me to the idea of scripting, which took me some time to grasp.
            Simply put, I came to learn that scripts are very useful when tackling unique tasks, and are amazing when those unique tasks come up very often.
            </description>
        </descriptions>
    </project>

    <project>
        <universalname>HotPursuit</universalname>
        <name>Hot Pursuit</name>
        <category>FPS</category>
        <languages>
            <language>C</language>
            <language>Unity 3D</language>
        </languages>
        <descriptions>
            <description>
            Now this was an interesting game that my university friends and I decided to collaborate often.
            One of my colleagues suggested we create a game that is similar to the FPS game SUPERHOT.
            In SUPERHOT, time only moves while you moved, and you have to use firearms or melee weapons to fight enemies.
            In our game that we've named Hot Pursuit (I know, very original indeed), the main character would also have a mechanic
            which slows time. But, instead of using firearms or melee weapons, the character has to pop up objects around them
            using a sort of ground slam. The character can then slow time, causing said objects to slow down while in the air,
            allowing the charcater to hit the object towards any target or enemy they are aiming at.
            </description>
            <description>
            As one of the members in a group of three, we split into 3 different areas to work on:
            Enemy AI, Time Slow + Pop Up Mechanic, and Smooth, Buttery Movement Controls.
            As a big fan of 3D platformers and FPS games with nice movement controls, I was put in charge of developing movement.
            </description>
            <description>
            As one of my only Unity 3D Projects (I stuck mainly to 2D), creating smooth and silky movement was a challenge.
            One of the team members helped me create a movement state system using stacks.
            While it took some time to grasp, I was able to understand how the system is able to seamlessly switch from
            one move state (walking) to another (running, crouching).
            You can also restrict moving into a specific movestate while in another move state (for example, you can't slide
            whilst walking, but you can slide when whilst running).
            I also went out of my way to revisit games which I highly enjoyed the movement in, and mimicked the feel of their controls.
            </description>
            <description>
            It was a very interesting project to work on which helped me learn many things from the use of raycasting to the particle system
            that Unity has to offer.
            </description>
        </descriptions>
    </project>

    <project>
        <universalname>BallGame</universalname>
        <name>Ball Game</name>
        <category>Unity</category>
        <languages>
            <language>C#</language>
            <language>Unity 3D</language>
        </languages>
        <descriptions>
            <description>
            Ball Game
            </description>
        </descriptions>
    </project>

    <project>
        <universalname>HTMLCanvas</universalname>
        <name>Canvas | JavaScript</name>
        <category>Web Development</category>
        <languages>
            <language>JavaScript</language>
            <language>HTML</language>
            <language>CSS</language>
        </languages>
        <descriptions>
            <description>
            Canvas | JavaScript
            </description>
        </descriptions>
    </project>

    <project>
        <universalname>AutonomousRobot</universalname>
        <name>Autonomous Robot</name>
        <category>Arduino</category>
        <languages>
            <language>C</language>
        </languages>
        <descriptions>
            <description>
            Autonomous Robot
            </description>
        </descriptions>
    </project>

    <project>
        <universalname>PortfolioWebsite</universalname>
        <name>Portfolio Website</name>
        <category>Web Development</category>
        <languages>
            <language>HTML</language>
            <language>CSS</language>
            <language>JavaScript</language>
            <language>JQuery</language>
        </languages>
        <descriptions>
            <description>
            Portfolio Website
            </description>
        </descriptions>
    </project>

    <project>
        <universalname>OpenGLTD</universalname>
        <name>OpenGL Tower Defense</name>
        <category>OpenGL</category>
        <languages>
            <language>C</language>
            <language>OpenGL</language>
            <language>freeglut</language>
            <language>GLEW</language>
        </languages>
        <descriptions>
            <description>
            OpenGL Tower Defense
            </description>
        </descriptions>
    </project>

</projects>